would you say thyroid is a distributor
of hormones um if thyroid is not
functioning well hypothyroidism will it
hinder trt from working
effectively So when you say thyroid is a
distributor of hormones the thyroid
secretes thyroid specific
hormones uh calcitonin in addition to
that but at the same time your thyroid
does not control your testosterone
production but if you're already on
trt your thyroid will control other
factors in your body including your
ability to metabolize and convert energy
so it's not necessarily going to hinder
your testosterone therapy but it will
certainly have a tremendous impact on
how you feel so if your thyroid is
malfunctioning your ability to remove
the symptoms that you initially saw to
your T4 may be hindered your
testosterone may be optimal at this
point after treatment however your
symptoms May linger because many of them
potentially were caused by other causes
and this holds true not just for thyroid
but really for anything we'll often find
guys that come back with an atom score
of let's say an eight out of 10 will
initiate proper trt treatment and once
their evaluation period has come around
and some of those symptoms have
alleviated they may still be a three out
of 10 it's a win but but there's still
work to be done and often times it is
not related to
testosterone it's it's more often than
not lifestyle you right we we find a lot
of anemia we find a lot of sleep apnea
we find a lot of uh poor diet um poor
exercise regimens so so lifestyle you
know poor Stress Management leading to
althetic loads over time that lead to
you know physiological pathology you
know if you're under duress or stress
for an extended period of time that does
break down physical aspects in your body
as well with with all that elevated you
know adrenaline and
cortisol so testosterone in of itself is
not a magic pill to fix all your
problems but the thyroid is definitely a
big one to look at as well especially
with fatigue you know dry or flaky skin
hair loss uh you know inability to lose
fat Etc
[Music]